<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ansible on kiennt26's home</title><link>https://ntk148v.github.io/tags/ansible/</link><description>Recent content in ansible on kiennt26's home</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 14:41:38 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ntk148v.github.io/tags/ansible/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Testing Ansible With Molecule</title><link>https://ntk148v.github.io/posts/testing-ansible-with-molecule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 14:41:38 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://ntk148v.github.io/posts/testing-ansible-with-molecule/</guid><description>The following content is rendered from my #til github. Testing Ansible with Molecule Source:
https://molecule.readthedocs.io/en/latest/getting-started/ https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2018/testing-your-ansible-roles-molecule Table of content:
Testing Ansible with Molecule 0. Problem 1. Introduction 2. Play with Molecule 2.1. Getting started 2.2. Custom Docker image 2.3. Test an existing role 0. Problem You wrote an Ansible playbook, good job, congratulations! Now you have to (should) check if the playbook works correctly. You may have multiple choices:</description></item><item><title>Ansitheus</title><link>https://ntk148v.github.io/posts/ansitheus/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 13:51:59 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://ntk148v.github.io/posts/ansitheus/</guid><description>Ansitheus: Ansible + Prometheus 1. Prometheus overview NOTE: Checkout the Prometheus official documentation.
Prometheus is an open-source systems monitoring &amp;amp; alerting toolkit originally built at SoundCloud.
1.1. Features a multi-dimensional data model with time series data identified by metric name &amp;amp; key/value pairs PromQL, a flexible query language to leverage this dimensionality no reliance on distributed storage; single server nodes are autonomous time series collection happens via a pull model over HTTP pushing time series is supported via an intermediary gateway targets are discovered via service discovery or static configuration multiple modes of graphing &amp;amp; dashboarding support 1.</description></item></channel></rss>